<problem markdown="Which of the following is not a good example of 'deadlock'?&#10;     ( ) Two students with bad eyesight need to study for the same midterm, but there is only one book and one pair of glasses: one grabs the book the other the glasses, but neither can start their studying.&#10;     (x) Two students with bad eyesight need to study for the same midterm, but there is only one book and one pair of glasses: one grabs the book and the glasses, but the second one cannot start his studying.&#10;     ( ) All of the above&#10;     ( ) None of the above&#10;     &#10;[explanation]&#10;In the second case, one of the students can complete his studying, then when he finishes his studying the book and glasses will be available for the second student to use. This is a good example of serial performance. Deadlock only happens in parallelism. Where some workers, who in this case are the students, cannot complete their task because they have sequential or the same orders.&#10;[explanation]&#10;" display_name="Quiz 8.7" showanswer="finished">
  <p>Which of the following is not a good example of 'deadlock'?</p>
  <multiplechoiceresponse>
    <choicegroup type="MultipleChoice">
      <choice correct="false">Two students with bad eyesight need to study for the same midterm, but there is only one book and one pair of glasses: one grabs the book the other the glasses, but neither can start their studying.</choice>
      <choice correct="true">Two students with bad eyesight need to study for the same midterm, but there is only one book and one pair of glasses: one grabs the book and the glasses, but the second one cannot start his studying.</choice>
      <choice correct="false">All of the above</choice>
      <choice correct="false">None of the above</choice>
    </choicegroup>
  </multiplechoiceresponse>
  <solution>
    <div class="detailed-solution">
      <p>Explanation</p>
      <p>In the second case, one of the students can complete his studying, then when he finishes his studying the book and glasses will be available for the second student to use. This is a good example of serial performance. Deadlock only happens in parallelism. Where some workers, who in this case are the students, cannot complete their task because they have sequential or the same orders.</p>
    </div>
  </solution>
</problem>
