<problem markdown="null" display_name="Quiz 6.4" showanswer="finished">
  <p>Trivia quesition:</p>
  <p>Which of the following statements is not true about <b>Alan Turing</b> ?</p>
  <multiplechoiceresponse>
    <choicegroup type="MultipleChoice">
      <choice correct="false">The Turing Award is awarded annually in his honor, for technical or theoretical contributions to the computing community.</choice>
      <choice correct="false">He helped win WWII by breaking German ciphers (encoded messages).</choice>
      <choice correct="false">He invented a very simple "Universal Machine" (henceforth called a Universal Turing Machine) and proved that his machine was just as powerful (in terms of what it could compute) as any machine that could ever be built.</choice>
      <choice correct="true">He eventually retired after a full career, as one of the most celebrated minds of his time.</choice>
    </choicegroup>
  </multiplechoiceresponse>
  <solution>
    <div class="detailed-solution">
      <p>Explanation</p>
      <p>Sadly, he lived at a time when British society did not tolerate his homosexuality. In 1952, he was charged with gross indecency, and given a choice between imprisonment or forced hormone treatment. He chose the treatment, which eventually made him impotent. Also, as a result of his conviction, his security clearance were revoked, preventing him from consulting for the British intelligence agency where he had been working.</p>
      <p>He was found dead in 1954, when he was only 41 years old -- the official cause of death was cyanide poisoning, and an inquest determined he had taken his own life. In 2009, Prime Minister Gordon Brown released a statement (after a petition was circulated with thousands of signatures urging the government to apologize for prosecuting him as a homosexual), saying: "So on behalf of the British government, and all those who live freely thanks to Alan's work I am very proud to say: we're sorry, you deserved so much better."</p>
    </div>
  </solution>
</problem>
